[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：这是下一个。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Here’s a next one.
编写一个接受二进制函数和参数的函数curry，并且
Write a function curry that takes a binary function and an argument, and
返回可以接受第二个参数的函数。
returns a function that can take a second argument.
在这里，我们将把我们编写的add函数传递给curry函数
Here we'll pass to the curry function the add function that we wrote this
早上3点。
morning and 3.
它将返回一个函数，该函数将向事物添加3。
It will return a function that will add 3 to things.
类似地，我们可以传递给curry乘法函数和5。
And similarly we could pass to curry the multiply function and 5.
它将返回一个将乘以5的函数。
And it will return a function that will multiply things by 5.
&GT；&GT；扬声器2：我们昨天做了咖喱。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: We did curry yesterday.
&gt；&gt；扬声器3：[听不见]一切都回到了原地。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: [INAUDIBLE] It all comes full circle.
&gt；&gt；[INAUDIBLE]&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：它是
&gt;&gt; [INAUDIBLE] &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: It's
当我介绍这个问题时，有些人振作起来，这并不少见。
not uncommon when I introduce this problem, that some people perk up.
他们走了，咖喱终于开始变得有趣了。
They go, Curry this is finally starting to get interesting.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 2：在前面的解决方案中，我们有一个var add f。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: In the previous solution we had a var add f.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：嗯哼。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Mm-hm.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 2：前面我们有一个函数add f。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: And earlier on we had a function add f.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yep.
&gt；&gt；Speaker 2：JS Lint抱怨这是一个重新定义。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: And JS Lint complains it's a redefinition.
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：没错。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: That's right.
&gt；&gt；演讲者2：是什么？
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: And is?
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：JS Lint是对的。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: JS Lint is right.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：好的。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Okay.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：好的，这里有一个咖喱函数。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Okay, so here's a curry function.
Curry接受一个二进制函数和第一个参数，
Curry takes a binary function and a first argument and
返回接受第二个参数的函数。
returns a function that takes a second argument.
并返回使用第一个AND函数调用二进制函数的结果
And returns the result of calling the binary function with the first and
第二个论点。
second arguments.
那么谁吃了咖喱，非常好。
So who got curry, very good.
如果你没有得到咖喱，现在就得到它，因为你以后会需要它。
If you didn't get curry, get it now because you'll going to need it later.
现在你可以用另一种方式写咖喱，
Now another way you could have written curry,
你可以使用我们之前写的提升函数。
is you could have used the lift function that we wrote earlier.
有人用过电梯吗？
Did anyone use lift f?
如果你这么做了，那就是额外的学分。
That would be extra credit, if you've done that.
所以，这个采用多个参数的函数的过程
So, this process of taking a function with multiple arguments and
将其转换为接受单个参数的多个函数称为转换(Currying)。
turning it into multiple functions that take a single argument is called currying.
它是以Haskell Curry的名字命名的，Haskell Curry是一位数学家，他做了很多工作
And it's named after Haskell Curry who is a mathematician who did a lot of work with
丘奇的Lambda演算。
Church's lambda calculus.
并且通过规范化所有函数以仅接受它所做的一个参数
And by normalizing all functions to take only one argument it made
很多手术更容易想到。
a lot of operations easier to think about.
有些人认为它应该被称为Schonfinkelization
Some people think it should be called Schonfinkelisation
因为之前有个叫Schon Finkel的人在做这件事，但是
because there is a fellow named Schon Finkel who is doing this stuff earlier but
我们称它为醋栗。
we're going to call it currying.
现在有些人希望咖喱能够使用以下功能
Now some people would like curry to be able to work with functions of
任意数量的参数。
any number of arguments.
使用JavaScript可以做到这一点。
And it's possible to do that with JavaScript.
它是可怕的，它是可怕的丑陋。
And it is horrible, it's terribly ugly.
所以，如果我想让这两个函数中的任何一个
So, if I want to have either the two functions take
任何数量的事情，而不仅仅是我们关心的一件事。
any number of things rather than just the one thing that we're concerned with.
你必须这样做，这是不可原谅的可怕，这是因为
You have to do that and it's inexcusably awful, and it's because
参数组并不是真正的数组，所以它不能正常工作，所以
the arguments array isn't really an array and so it doesn't work right, and so
为了让事情发生，你必须做所有这些技巧。
you have to do all these tricks in order to get things to happen.
我不打算解释它的作用，因为
I'm not going to explain what this does because
我只是不想在上面浪费时间，太可怕了。
I just don't want to waste time on it, it's awful.
因此，由于这种可怕。
And so because of this awfulness.
我们今天编写的所有函数只需要固定数量的
All of the functions that we write today will only take a fixed number of
争论。
arguments.
所以我们将有一元函数，将接受一个参数，并且
So we'll have unary functions will take one argument, and
二进制函数将接受两个参数，即使我们有很多应用程序
binary functions will take two arguments even though lots of the applications we're
将要做的事情真的希望它是可变的。
going to do would really like it to be variable.
我不想你在这上面浪费时间，因为你可以看到那里，
I don't want you have to waste your time on this because you can see there,
有一大堆事情都和咖喱无关。
there's a whole lot of stuff going on that has nothing to do with curry.
现在ES6中，它正开始寻找实现的方法。
Now in ES6, which is starting to find its way into implementations.
省略号运算符和点运算符有一些新的语法。
There is some new syntax with the ellipsis operator the dot dot dot operator.
如果你把省略号放在参数列表中，说明的是，
And if you put the ellipsis in a parameter list, what that says is, take
所有其余的参数将它们放入一个数组中
all of the rest of the arguments all the remaining arguments put them into an array
并将该数组绑定到该参数，这样就更清晰了。
and bind that array to that parameter, and that is so much cleaner.
然后在调用端的参数列表中，如果您转到点和
And then on the call side in an argument list, if you go dot dot dot and
那里有一个数组，它说把这个数组展开。
there is an array there, it says take that array and spread it out.
因此数组的每个元素都是一个单独的参数。
So each element of the array will be a separate argument.
通过这样做，我们得到了这个版本的咖喱函数
And so by doing that, we've got this version of the curry function which
看起来和第一个完全一样，只是里面有注释，
looks exactly like the first one except it's got the annotations in it which says,
这就是你可以有多个事物被传递的地方。
this is where you can have a multiple number of things being passed.
这两个都做着完全相同的事情，你更喜欢读哪一个？
Both of these do exactly the same thing, which one would you rather be reading?
我猜这是第二个。
I'm guessing it be the second one.
所以当ES6变得无处不在时，我会改变这个课程，所以
So when ES6 becomes everywhere, then I'll change this course so
我们将编写看起来像这样的函数。
that we'll be writing functions that look like that.
是啊。&gt；&gt；演讲者4：这是我的问题
Yeah. &gt;&gt; Speaker 4: That's kind of questions I
昨天给你的，但现在已经很清楚了。
had for you yesterday, but it's clear now.
就像，当你看到ES32的到来，
So like, when you were seeing the advent from ES32,
像ES5一样，浏览器需要很长时间才能适应？
like ES5, that take like a long time for browsers to adapt?
或者你看到我们现在移动得更快了吗？
Or do you see us moving a little faster now or
只是需要很长时间才能[INAUDIBLE]。
is it just going to take quite a while to [INAUDIBLE].
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：更快的是ES5的大挂断是IE的问题。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: It's faster that the big hangup with ES5 was the IE problem.
IE已经不是以前那样的问题了。
And IE is not nearly the problem that it was before.
所有其他浏览器都在更新。
And all of the other browsers are out updating.
所以问题不在于传播和收养。
So the problem isn't propagation and adoption.
现在的问题只是实现。
The problem is now just implementation.
所以我希望我们能更快地把所有的东西都拿出来。
So I'm hoping that we'll get all of the stuff out much faster.
所以不管怎样，省略号将是我第二个最喜欢的特性ES6，当和
So anyway, Ellipsis will be my second most favorite feature ES6, when and
如果它能完成，那将是很好的，但同时我们只是
if it ever gets finished so that will be great but in the mean time we're only
会关注带有固定数量参数的函数，好吗？
gonna be concerned with functions taking a fixed number of arguments, Okay?
那么我们准备好下一个了吗？
So we're ready for the next one?
下一个问题会有点不同，因为你不是
This next problem is going to be a little bit different because you are not
准备编写任何新的函数。
going to write any new functions.
相反，您将使用我们已经编写的函数。
Instead you're going to be using functions that we have already written.
因此，无需编写任何新函数，就可以展示创建inc函数的三种方法。
So without writing any new functions show three ways to create the inc function.
inc函数将数字加1并返回它。
The inc function adds one to a number and returns it.
因此，如果您将5传递给inc，它将返回6。
So if you pass five to inc it will return six.
所以你要调用一个函数，它将创建inc函数。
And so you're going to call a function, which will create the inc function.
并且您将展示三种不同的方法来实现这一点，使用您所使用的函数
And you're going to show three different ways to do that using functions you've
已经写好了。
already written.
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：下面是做公司的三种方式。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So here are three ways to do inc.
第一个是1的加法f，谁得到了这个？
First one is add f of 1, who got that one?
好的，下一个是加法和1的升力f，谁知道了？
Okay, the next is lift f of add and 1, who got that?
和咖喱的Add和1谁收到了？
And curry of add and 1 who got that?
谁把这三个都拿走了？
And who got all three?
非常好，所以这说明了函数式编程的第一个规则，即，
Very good, so this illustrates the first rule of functional programming which is,
让函数来完成这项工作。
let the functions do the work.
如果您已经编写了完成所需操作的函数，
If you've already written a function that does what you need,
你不需要再写一个。
you don't need to write another one.